William Mansfield Clark Papers 1903-1964 Mss.B.C547
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1903-1964; 3.5 lin. feet
  - Hart, Thomas C., 1963 (Box 3)
  - Harte, Robert A. (Box 3)
  - Hartung, Walter H., 1952 (Box 3)
  - Haseman, J. D. (Box 3)
  - Hastings, A. Baird, 1935-1963, n.d. (Box 3)
    -see also Ser. I, Van Wyk, Judson J.
    -see also Ser. II, Hastings, A. Baird
    -see also Ser. V, [Hastings, A. Baird] "The Scientific Career of William Mansfield Clark..."
  - Hastings, J. Woodland, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Hearon, John Z. (Box 3)
    -see Ser. I, Caraway, Wendell T.
  - Heidelberger, Michael, 1946 (Box 3)
    -see also Ser. II, Cinquantenaire De La Mort De Pasteur
  - Hektoen, Ludvig, 1920 (Box 3)
    Jordan, Edwin O.
  - Hellerman, Leslie, 1947, n.d. (Box 3)
    -see also Ser. I, Clark, Miriam G[oddard]
    -see also Ser. II, "Bug Battery"
    -see also Ser. VI, [JHU Medical School, Clark's Laboratory Staff]
    -see also Oversized
  - Henderson, R. W., 1955, 1960, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Herriott, Roger M., 1948-1950, 1952 (Box 3)
    -see also Ser. I, Taylor, W. Rowland
  - Hickey, Helen Sullivan, 1946 (Box 3)
  - Hill, Jus[?] (Box 3)
  - Hitchcock, David I., 1948 (Box 3)
  - Hixson, A. W. (Box 3)
  - Höber, R., 1926 (Box 3)
  - Hoch, Hans, 1954 (Box 3)
  - Hocking, George M. (Box 3)
  - Hoey, Allan S., 1944 (Box 3)
  - Holcomb, W. F. (Box 3)
  - Holm, George E. (Box 3)
  - Holmes, W. C. (Box 3)
  - [H]olthoff, N. W. (Box 3)
  - Hoover, Dick M. (Box 3)
    -see Ser. I, the Williams & Wilkins Co.
  - The Hotchkiss School, 1903, 1938, 1940, 1955, n.d. (Box 3)
    Buckner, H. G.
    McKnight, William G., Jr.
    Morton, Warren
    Van Santvoord, George
    Wallace, Robert L.
    -see also Ser. I, Estill, Joe Garner
    -see also Ser. II, The Hotchkiss School
  - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1941 (Box 3)
    Fuller, Henry R.
  - Howell, William H., 1925, 1939 (Box 3)
  - Huber, G. Carl (Box 3)
  - Hucker, G. J. (Box 3)
    -see Ser. I, The American Society of Bacteriologists
  - Huggins, Charles (Box 3)
  - Hughes, Walter, 1958, n.d. (Box 3)
  - H[y]lett, George A., 1922 (Box 3)
  - Hyman, Edward S., 1961 (Box 3)
  - Hynson, Westcott & Dunning, 1919 (Box 3)
    Dunning, H. A. Brown
    -see also Ser. I, US Department of Commerce
  - Indicators, 1961-1962 (Box 3)
    Bishop, E.
  - Industrial and Engineering Chemistry, 1944 (Box 3)
    Murphy, Walter J.
  - Ingle, Dwight J. (Box 3)
    -see Ser. I, Perspectives in Biology
  - Institut Pasteur (Box 3)
  - The Institute of Paper Chemistry (Box 3)
  - International Congress of Pure and Applied Chemistry (12th), 1950 (Box 3)
    Fisher, Harry L.
  - International Critical Tables of Numerical Data of Physics, Chemistry and Technology, 1923, 1925 (Box 3)
  - International Union of Biochemistry. Commission on Enzymes, 1962-1963 (Box 3)
    Colowick, Sidney L.
    Lehninger, Albert L.
    Webb, [Edwin] C.
    -see also Ser. IV, "A Critique..."
  - International Union of Pure and Applied Chemistry (Box 3)
  - Irvin, J. Logan, 1950-1959 (Box 3)
    Worked in WMC's lab
    Brinkhous, K. M.
    Guggenheim Fellowships
    Moe, [Henry Allen]
  - Irwin, Marian (Box 3)
  - Jackson, Perry Y., 1956 (Box 3)
  - Jackson, R. [T.] (Box 3)
  - Jacobs, M. H. (Box 3)
  - Jacobsohn, I. M. (Box 3)
    -see Ser. I, [Steglitz], Julius
  - Jaeger, Alfred (Box 3)
  - Jaffe, Herbert, 1948 (Box 3)
  - Japanese Embassy, 1923 (Box 3)
  - Jefferson Medical College, 1930 (Box 3)
    Morse, Withrow
  - Jensen, Orla, 1924 (Box 3)
  - Jewett, Frank B. (Box 3)
    -see Ser. I, NAS Advisory Committee on Biologic Warfare
    -see Ser. II, Frank B. Jewett Fellowships in the Physical Sciences
    -see Ser. V, NAS...
  - Johns Hopkins Hospital, 1946, 1952 (Box 3)
    Barnes, Frederick W., Jr.
    Gibbs, John S.
    Te Linde, Richard W.
  - Johns Hopkins Medical Society, n.d. (Box 3)
    Stenographer's notes re: "starling theory"
    Chinard, [Francis P.]
    Flexner, [Simon]
  - Johns Hopkins University (JHU), 1909-1963 (Box 4)
    Ames, Joseph [S.]
    Bronk, Detlev
    Burford, William B., III
    Cox, R. T.
    Eisenhower, [Milton S.]
    Garland, Charles S.
    Institute for Cooperative Research
    Macaulay, P. Stewart
    Poole, Lynn
    Remsen, Ira
    Shaffer, G. Wilson
    Taylor, Wesley A.
    -see also Ser. II, Bowman, Isaiah
    -see also Ser. II, JHU...
  - JHU Alumni Association, 1952-1955 (Box 4)
    Steinwald, Osmar P.
    Dunning, J. H. Fitzgerald
    -see also Ser. I, Lawson, W. E.
  - JHU Chemistry Department, 1952-1959 (Box 4)
    McElroy, William D.
  - JHU Committee on the Chemistry Department, 1952 (Box 4)
    Cloos, Ernst
    Koski, Walter S.
    Reid, Evans B.
    Wolman, Abel
  - JHU Institute for Cooperative Research (Box 4)
  - JHU McCollum-Pratt Institute, 1952-1959 (Box 4)
    -see Ser. I, JHU Chemistry Department
  - JHU Medical School, 1927-1961 (Box 4)
    Abel, John J.
    Archibald, R. M.
    Burgan, H. C.
    Dwek, Joseph
    Friedenwald, Jonas S.
    Jones, Walter
    Marshall, E. K., Jr.
    -see also Ser. VI, [JHU Medical School...]
  - JHU Medical School, Committees, 1929, 1932, 1950 (Box 4)
    re: admissions, curriculum, pharmacology & instruction
    [Chinard], Francis
    -see also Ser. V, JHU Medical School, "Interim Report..."
  - JHU Medical School, Herter Lectureship Committee, 1948-1951 (Box 4)
    Bard, Phil[ip]
    Crosby, Edwin L.
    Dieke, H. G.
    Grafflin, Allan L.
    Lilienthal, Joseph L., Jr.
    Linderstrøm-Lang, K.
    Morgan, Russell H.
    Reed, Lowell J.
    Rich, Arnold R.
    Turner, Tommy
    -see also Ser. II, JHU Medical School, Lecture Programs
  - JHU Medical School, Physiological Chemistry Department (Box 4)
  - JHU Remsen Memorial Lectures, 1950, 1952 (Box 4)
    Fowler, Robert D.
    -see also Ser. I, Chemical and Engineering News
    -see also Ser. II, JHU Remsen Memorial Lectures
    -see also Ser. IV, Remsen Memorial Lectures--Notes
    -see also Ser. IV, "Some Reflections on the Coupling of Chemical Processes and the Biochemical Implications"
  - JHU Treasurer, 1933, 1952-1954 (Box 4)
    Baker, Henry S.
    Corless, Grace Grimmel
  - JHU Undergraduate Chemistry Club, 1950 (Box 4)
  - Johnson, A. Leroy, 1949 (Box 4)
  - Walter J. Johnson, Inc., 1952-1962, n.d. (Box 4)
    Sale of journals
    Ashley-Ratcliff Corp.
    Dimler, Fred J.
    Jaeger, Alfred
    The Periodical Mart
  - Johnston, John (Box 4)
    -see Ser. I, ACS
  - Johri, B. M., 1957 (Box 4)
  - Jones, Benjamin B. (Box 4)
  - Jones, Walter (Box 4)
    -see Ser. I, JHU School of Medicine
    -see Ser. I, "Biographical Memoir of Walter (Jennings) Jones, 1865-1935"
  - Jordan, Edwin O., 1927 (Box 4)
    Falk, I. S.
    -see also Ser. I, Hektoen, Ludvig
  - Journal of the American Chemical Society, 1921-1961 (Box 4)
    Lamb, Arthur B.
    Noyes, W. Albert
  - Journal of Bacteriology, 1933, 1944 (Box 4)
    -see also Ser. I, Society of American Bacteriologists
    -see also Ser. IV, "Evolution Toward a Mature Scientific Literature"
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry (Box 4)
    AAAS
    Carter, Herbert
    Clarke, Hans T.
    Cullen, Glenn E.
    Edsall, John T.
    Elvehjem, Conrad A.
    Haseman, J. D.
    Luck J. Murray
    Mattill, Henry A.
    Wintersteiner, O[skar]
    - Folder 1, 1933-1955 (Box 4)
    - Folder 2, 1956-1961 (Box 4)
  - Journal of Colloid Science, 1952 (Box 4)
    Ricci, John E.
    -see also Ser. V, Sollner, Karl...
  - Kamen, Martin D., 1955, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Kaplan, Nathan, 1957 (Box 4)
  - Kappa Mu Sigma, 1927 (Box 4)
    Kent Chemical Laboratory
    Smith, Constance
  - Kaufman, Leo, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Kennedy, Thomas J., Jr., 1947 (Box 4)
  - Kent Chemical Laboratory (Box 4)
    -see Ser. I, Kappa Mu Sigma
  - [K]err, J. D. (Box 4)
  - King, C. G. (Box 4)
  - [Kirby, George H.] (Box 4)
  - Kirby, J. E. (Box 4)
  - Kirk, Grayson (Box 4)
    -see Ser. I, Columbia Univeristy
  - Kirk, (Gen.) Norman T. (Box 4)
  - Kluyver, A. J., 1925-1926 (Box 4)
  - Koepfli, J. B., [1942], 1944 (Box 4)
  - Kohman, E. F. (Box 4)
    -see Ser. I, Campbell Soup Company
  - Kopeloff, Nicholas, 1934, 1936 (Box 4)
  - Kornberg, Arthur, 1953 (Box 4)
  - Koski, Walter S. (Box 4)
  - Kough, Isabella, 1953 (Box 4)
  - Krebs, Hans Adolf, 1953 (Box 4)
  - Kühnau, Joachim, 1927 (Box 4)
    In German
  - Kulka, J. P., 1951 (Box 4)
  - Labeyrie, Françoise, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Ladd, William S. (Box 4)
    -see Ser. I, Cornell University Medical College
  - Lakeville Journal (Lakeville, Conn.), n.d. (Box 4)
    Letter re: McCarthyism
  - Lamb, Arthur B. (Box 4)
    -see Ser. I, Journal of the American Chemical Society
  - La Mer, Victor K., 1922 (Box 4)
    Baker, Lillian
    -see also Ser. I, ACS
    -see also Ser. I, Journal of Colloid Science
  - LaMotte, Frank L. (Box 4)
    -see Ser. I, LaMotte Chemical Products Company
  - LaMotte Chemical Products Company, 1919-1921, 1958-1959 (Box 4)
    LaMotte, Frank L.
  - Lampson, Lucy (Box 4)
    -see Ser. I, Thomas R. Wagner Agency
  - The Lancet, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Landmann, Paul E. (Box 4)
  - Lansdale, Florence (Box 4)
  - Lapp, C. J. (Box 4)
  - Lasagna, Louis, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Lawson, W. E., 1952 (Box 4)
    -see also Ser. I, JHU Alumni Association
  - Lea & Febiger Publishers, 1919, 1945-1960, n.d. (Box 4)
    Boland, V. J.
    Spahr, John R.
    -see also Ser. I, Gentzkow, C. J.
    -see also Ser. I, Simmons, (Gen.) James S.
    -see also Ser. IV, "Hydrogen Ion Determinations"...
  - Leach, S. J., 1954 (Box 4)
  - Leaders in American Science, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Leake, J. P., 1923 (Box 4)
  - Lee, John W. (Box 4)
  - The Leeds & Northrup Company, 1919-1920, 1924, 1953 (Box 4)
  - Lehninger, A. L., 1952-1958 (Box 4)
    -see also Ser. II, Lehninger, A. L.
  - Lemberg, Rudolf, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Leve[ne], P. A., 1925, 1927 (Box 4)
  - Lever, Walter F. (Box 4)
  - Leviton, A. (Box 4)
  - Lewis, George T., 1952 (Box 4)
  - Lewis, Harry F. (Box 4)
    -see Ser. I, The Institute of Paper Chemistry
  - Lilienthal, Joseph L., Jr. (Box 4)
    -see Ser. I, JHU Herter Lectureship Committee
  - Lilly Research Grants Committee, 1952-1953 (Box 4)
  - Lilly Research Laboratories, 1949 (Box 4)
    Campbell, Edward D.
  - Linderstrøm-Lang, K. (Box 4)
  - Ling, Gilbert, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Lipmann, Fritz, 1960 (Box 5)
  - Livingston, Burton E., 1934 (Box 5)
  - "Lloyd", 1920-1921, 1927 (Box 5)
    Rockefeller Inst., & Harvard
  - Loeb, Jacques, 1920-1922 (Box 5)
    -see also Ser. IV, Proteins and the Theory Colloidal Behavior
  - Loeb, Robert F., 1944 (Box 5)
    -see also Ser. I, Chinard, Francis P.
  - Long, Cyril (Box 5)
    -see Ser. I, Biochemist's Handbook
  - Long, P. H., 1942 (Box 5)
  - Longcope, Warfield T. (Box 5)
  - Longenecker, William, 1948 (Box 5)
  - Lowe, Harry J., 1953-1957 (Box 5)
    Savage, W.
  - Lowenhart, Arthur S., 1927, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Lubs, H. A., 1920-1929, 1944-1956 (Box 5)
    Perkins, M. A.
    -see also Ser. I, E. I. du Pont de Nemours & Company
    -see also Ser. II, Lubs, H. A.
  - Luck, J. Murray, 1952, n.d. (Box 5)
    -see also Ser. I, Annual Review of Biochemistry
  - Lynch, Ruth S. (Box 5)
  - MacBain, James W., 1927 (Box 5)
  - MacCallum, W. G., 1927 (Box 5)
  - McCarthy, (Sen.) Joseph, 1950 (Box 5)
  - McClendon, J. F., [1919] (Box 5)
  - McCollum, E. V., 1952 (Box 5)
    re: Remsen Memorial Lecture
  - McCoy, George W. (Box 5)
  - McDermott, F. A., 1930, n.d. (Box 5)
  - McElfresh, William E. (Box 5)
  - McElroy, William D. (Box 5)
    -see Ser. I, Nobel Committee. Medicine
  - MacFadyen, Douglas A. (Box 5)
    -see Ser. I, Noyes, W. A., Jr.
    -see Ser. I. The Presbyterian Hospital of the City of Chicago
    -see Ser. II, The Presbyterian Hospital of the City of Chicago
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc., 1934, 1958-1963 (Box 5)
    Thompson, James S.
  - McGregor, James H., 1949 (Box 5)
  - McKnight, William G., Jr. (Box 5)
  - McLean, Franklin C., 1944 (Box 5)
    Peters, John P.
  - McMahon, (Sen.) Brien, 1950 (Box 5)
    re: McCarthy
  - MacMillin, R. B (Box 5)
    -see Ser. I, the Mathieson Alkali Works, (Inc.)
  - Macaulay, P. Stewart (Box 5)
  - Major, Randolph T. (Box 5)
  - Marshall, E. K., Jr. (Box 5)
    -see Ser. I, Lasagna, Louis
  - Maryland. Department of Health, 1920-1925, 1934 (Box 5)
    Randall, Wyatt W.
  - Maryland Society for Medical Research, 1950 (Box 5)
  - Maryland Society of Bacteriologists, 1932 (Box 5)
  - Marvel, C. S. (Box 5)
  - Massey, Vincent, 1959 (Box 5)
  - Masson & Cie., Editeurs, 1924 (Box 5)
    some in French
  - Mattill, Henry A. (Box 5)
    -see Ser. I, The Journal of Biological Chemistry
  - The Mathieson Alkali Works (Inc.), 1926 (Box 5)
    MacMillin R. B.
  - Maumenee, [Ed], 1962 (Box 5)
  - Maxcy, Carroll L. (Box 5)
  - May, Stephen, 1946 (Box 5)
  - Mayer, Joseph E., 1948, n.d. (Box 5)
    Streeter, George
  - Mayo Clinic (Box 5)
  - Mears, Brainerd (Box 5)
  - Mears, Leverett (Box 5)
  - Medal for Merit Board (Box 5)
    -see Ser. I, President's Certificate of Merit
  - Memorial Center for Cancer and Allied Diseases, 1952 (Box 5)
    Rhoads, C. P.
  - Mendel, L. B., 1923 (Box 5)
  - Merck, George W. (Box 5)
    -see Ser. I, NAS Advisory
    Committee on Biologic Warfare
  - Merck & Company, Inc. (Box 5)
  - G. & C. Merriam Company, 1958 (Box 5)
  - Wm. S. Merrell Company (Box 5)
  - Merrill, Alice T., 1952 (Box 5)
  - Metal Coordination in the Medical Sciences, 1960 (Box 5)
    Proposed int'l conference
    Cotzias, George C.
  - Meyer, Adolf, 1920 (Box 5)
    Fowle,
    -see also Ser. II, Meyer, Adolf
  - Meyer, H. C. (Box 5)
    -see Ser. I, Foote Mineral Company, Inc.
  - Michaelis, Hedwig (Box 5)
    -see Ser. I, Michaelis, Leonor
  - Michaelis, Leonor, 1920-1924, 1943-1950 (Box 5)
    Some in German
    Michaelis, Hedwig
    -see also Ser. I, McGregor, James H.
    -see also Ser. IV, ["Leonor Michaelis: 1875-1949"]
    -see also Ser. V, Michaelis, Leonor. "The Mechanism of Autoxidation.."
  - Middleswart, (Gen.) W. H. (Box 5)
  - Miller, C. Phillip (Box 5)
    -see Ser. I, The Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology
    -see Ser. I, University of Chicago
  - Miller, Lewis B., 1925 (Box 5)
  - Miller, Robert C., 1925 (Box 5)
  - Milner, R. D., 1921 (Box 5)
  - Miner, Eunice Thomas (Box 5)
    -see Ser. I, The New York Academy of Sciences
  - Miner, Harlan S. (Box 5)
    -see Ser. I, Welsbach Company
  - Moe, [Henry Allen] (Box 5)
  - Montgomery, Jack P. (Box 5)
  - Moody, Herbert R. (Box 5)
  - Moore, Stanford (Box 5)
  - Morey, George W., 1954 (Box 5)
  - Morgan, D. P. (Box 5)
  - Morgan, Russell H. (Box 5)
  - Morgulis, Sergiu[s], 1949, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Morse, Withrow (Box 5)
    -see Ser. I, Jefferson Medical College
  - Morton, Warren (Box 5)
  - Moura, Gonçalves J. (Box 5)
  - Mudd, Stuart, 1934 (Box 5)
  - Mueller, J. Howard (Box 5)
  - Müller, Otto H., 1955 (Box 5)
  - Murphy, Walter J. (Box 5)
    -see Ser. I, Industrial and Engineering Chemistry
  - Nabisco (Box 5)
  - Nassau Smelting & Refining, Inc., 1944-1945 (Box 5)
  - NAS, 1928-1963 (Box 5)
    Cannon, Walter B
    Forrestal, James
    Longcope, Warfield T.
    Nassau Smelting & Refining, Inc.
    Richards A. N.
    Stimson, Henry L.
    Willard F. W.
    -see also Ser. II, NAS
    -see also Ser. V, NAS...
  - NAS Advisory Committee on Biologic Warfare, 1944-1946 (Box 5)
    "ABC" and "DEF" Committees
    Merck, George W.
    Mueller, J. Howard
    Pepper, O. H. Perry
    Sarles, William Bowen
    US Army. Office of Chief of Chemical Warfare Service
    -see also Ser. II, NAS Advisory Committee on Biologic Warfare
  - National Aniline & Chemical Company (Box 5)
  - National Biscuit Company, 1922 (Box 5)
    Davis, Clarke E.
  - National Cyclopedia of American Biography (Box 5)
  - National Defense Research Committee, 1941-1942 (Box 5)
    -see also Ser. I, National Resource Planning Board
    -see also, Ser. II, National Defense Research Committee
  - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis (Box 5)
    -see Ser. I, Van Wyk, Judson J.
  - National Galleries of New York, 1941 (Box 5)
    re: WMC photos
  - National Heart Council. Report on Dr. Ephraim Shorr. (Box 5)
    -see Ser. I, US Public Health Service, National Institutes of Health
  - National Lime Association, 1920 (Box 5)
    Fippin, E. O.
  - NRC, 1917, 1927-1963 (Box 5)
    Advisory Commission of the Council of National Defense
    Albritton, Errett C.
    American Cyanamid Company
    [Bard, Philip]
    Bartlett, Paul D.
    Bass, L. W.
    Bogert, Marston T.
    Brickwedde, F. G.
    Cushing, (Adm.) [H.]
    Doriot, (Gen.) Georges F.
    Eisenhart, L. P.
    Gross, Paul
    Gryder, John W.
    Handbook of Biological Data
    Harrison, Ross G.
    Huber, G. Carl
    The Institute of Paper Chemistry
    International Union of Pure and Applied Chemistry
    Lapp, C. J.
    Lewis, Harry F.
    Middleswart, (Gen.) W. H.
    Moody, Herbert R.
    Nicholas, J. S.
    Noyes, W. Albert, Jr.
    Preisler, Paul W. O.
    Ray, O. M.
    Spaulding, John H.
    Stock, C. Chester
    Stotz, E. H.
    Swain, R. C.
    Vaughan, V. C.
    Weisiger, James R.
    Winternitz, M. C.
    -see also Ser. II, NRC
  - NRC Antimalarial Drug Program (Box 5)
    Abbott Laboratories
    Adams, Roger
    Adkins, Homer
    American Public Health Association Board for the Coordination of Malarial Studies
    Carden, George A., Jr.
    Chen, K. K.
    Cromwell, Norman H.
    de Kruif, Paul
    Dieuaide, (Lt. Co.) Francis R.
    Dochez, A. R.
    E. I. du Pont de Nemours & Company
    Gilman, Henry
    Hocking, George M.
    Holcomb, W. F.
    Kirby, J. E.
    Kirk, (General) Norman T.
    Lee, John W.
    Marvel, C. S.
    Wm. S. Merrell Company
    NAS
    Office for Emergency Management
    Parke, Davis & Company
    S. B. Penick & Company
    Pitman-Moore Company
    Powers, E. L., Jr.
    Shannon, James A.
    Shelton, Robert S.
    Shriner, Ralph L.
    Sweet, L. A.
    Tainter, [M.] L.
    Van Campen, M. G., Jr.
    Volwiler, E. H.
    Willard, Fred W.
    Winthrop Chemical Company
    Wiselogle, Frederick
    -see also Ser. II, NRC Antimalarial Drug Program...
    -see also Ser. II, Symposium on the Biochemistry of Malarial Parasites...
    -see also Ser. IV, "History"
    -see also Ser. IV, "Review of the Present Arrangements..."
    -see also Ser. IV, "A Survey of Antimalarial Drugs..."
    -see also Ser. V, Antimalarial Drug Program...
    - Folder 1, 1942-1944 (Box 5)
    - Folder 2, 1944 (Box 5)
    - Folder 3, 1944-1946, n.d. (Box 5)
    - Folder 4, [1944 March] (Box 5)
  - NRC Fellowship in Medical Sciences (Box 5)
  - NRC Office of Critical Tables, 1957-1963 (Box 5)
    Elderfield, Robert C.
    Harte, Robert A.
    Moore, Stanford
    Putnam, Frank W.
    Snell, Esmond E.
    Sperry, Warren M.
    Stetten, DeWitt, Jr.
    Waddington, Guy
    -see also Ser. I, International Critical Tables...
  - National Resources Planning Board, 1941 (Box 6)
    Carmichael, Leonard
    National Defense Research
    Committee
  - Needham, Dorothy Moyle (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, Needham, Joseph
  - Needham, Joseph, 1925-1926 (Box 6)
    Needham, Dorothy Moyle
    -see also Ser. V, Needham, Joseph...
  - Neill, James (Box 6)
  - Neurath, Hans, 1954 (Box 6)
  - The New York Academy of Sciences, 1960 (Box 6)
    Miner, Eunice Thomas
    -see also Ser. II, Conference on Energy Relationships in Enzyme Reactions
  - Nicholas, J. S. (Box 6)
  - Nightingale (Box 6)
  - Niles, Emory H. (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, "Barnett Cohen, 1891-1952: An Appreciation"
  - Nobel Committee. Medicine, 1952-1953 (Box 6)
    re: recommendation of Beadle and Tatum
    Mc Elroy, W. D.
  - Noyes, William A. (Box 6)
  - Noyes, W. Albert., Jr., 1953 (Box 6)
    Mac Fadyen, Douglas
    -see also Ser. I, Journal of the American Chemical Society
  - Nyburg, Sidney L., 1952-1953 (Box 6)
    re: Estate of Barnett Cohen
  - Ochoa, Severo, 1957 (Box 6)
    -see also Ser. I, Grafflin, Allan L.
  - Office for Emergency Management (Box 6)
  - Office of Scientific Research and Development, 1941-1945 (Box 6)
    Smith, Homer W.
  - Okuda, Y., 1921 (Box 6)
  - Osborne, W. A., 1920 (Box 6)
  - Oster, Gerald (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn
  - Otto, Belle, 1952 (Box 6)
  - Otto, Gilbert, 1952 (Box 6)
    -see also Ser. II, "Barnett Cohen, 1895-1952: An Appreciation"
  - Papish, J., 1934 (Box 6)
  - Park, Edwards A. (Box 6)
    -see Ser. II, Park, Edwards A.
    -see Ser. VI, Park, Edwards A.
  - Parke, Davis & Company, 1945 (Box 6)
  - Parker, Frank S., 1954 (Box 6)
  - Parker, H. C. (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, The Leeds & Northrup Company
  - Parkinson, N. A. (Box 6)
  - Parks, George S., 1958-1959 (Box 6)
  - Parsons, Charles L. (Box 6)
  - The Passano Foundation, Inc., 1945 (Box 6)
    Cohn,
    Gill, Robert S.
    -see also Ser. II, Passano Award
  - Patterson, Austin M., 1932 (Box 6)
  - Pavlov, V. A., 1926 (Box 6)
  - Peltier, George L. (Box 6)
  - S. B. Penick & Company (Box 6)
  - Pennsylvania. Department of Health, 1924 (Box 6)
    Daniels, F. E.
  - Pepper, O. H. Perry (Box 6)
  - Pepper, William (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, Univeristy of Pennsylvania
  - Pergamon Press, 1959 (Box 6)
  - The Periodical Mart (Box 6)
  - Perkins, M. A. (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, Lubs, H. A.
  - Perlzweig, William A., 1927, 1944, 1948 (Box 6)
  - Perspectives in Biology, 1958-1960 (Box 6)
    Ingle, Dwight J.
  - Peters, John P. (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, Mc Lean, Franklin C.
  - Pfund, A. H. (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, Phi Beta Kappa Society
  - Phelps, Evart B. (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, Wallace & Tiernan Co., Inc.
  - Phi Beta Kappa Society, 1929, 1941-1942, 1946 (Box 6)
    Pfund, A. H.
  - Phi Beta Pi Fraternity, 1948-1949 (Box 6)
  - Phi Lambda Upsilon, 1938 (Box 6)
    Starr, Charles D.
  - Phillips, E. F. (Box 6)
  - Phillips, Max (Box 6)
  - Pierce, Harold B., 1934 (Box 6)
  - Pijoan, Michel, 1948 (Box 6)
  - Pitman-Moore Company (Box 6)
  - Podgorny, A. A., 1958 (Box 6)
    re: treatment of Linus Pauling in Time; scientists
  - Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1944, 1952 (Box 6)
    Oster, Gerald
    Smith, Gilbert B. L.
    -See also Ser. II, Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn
  - Ponder, Eric (Box 6)
  - Poole, Lynn D. (Box 6)
  - Porter, Curt C. (Box 6)
  - Powers, E. L., Jr. (Box 6)
  - Preisler, Paul, 1957-1960 (Box 6)
  - The Presbyterian Hospital of the City of Chicago, 1947 (Box 6)
    Mac Fadyen, Douglas A.
    -see also Ser. II, The Presbyterian Hospital of the City of Chicago
  - President's Certificate of Merit, 1948 (Box 6)
    Shreve, (Col.) Arthur L.
  - Pullen, E. W. (Box 6)
  - Putnam, Frank W (Box 6)
  - Quarterly Review of Biology, 1953 (Box 6)
    Glass, H. Bentley
  - Randall, Wyatt W. (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, Maryland. Department of Health
  - Rapkine, Louis, 1925-1951 (Box 6)
  - Rawl, B. H. (Box 6)
  - Ray, O. M. (Box 6)
  - Read, Bernard E., 1939 (Box 6)
  - Reed, Lowell, 1959 (Box 6)
  - Reid, Evans B. (Box 6)
  - Remsen, Ira (Box 6)
  - Research Corporation (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, Harbury, Henry
  - Reynolds, H. (Box 6)
  - Reznikoff, Paul (Box 6)
    -see Ser. II, "Barnett Cohen, 1895-1952: An Appreciation"
  - Rhoads, C. P. (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, Memorial Center for Cancer and Allied Diseases
  - Ricci, John E. (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, Journal of Colloid Science
    -see Ser. IV, Hydrogen Ion Concentration--Review
  - Rich, Arnold R., 1934, 1950-1952 (Box 6)
  - Richards, A. N., 1950 (Box 6)
    -see also Ser. I, University of Pennsylvania
  - Richardson, Emily G., [ca. 1953] (Box 6)
  - Richardson, G. M. (Box 6)
  - Richardson, Ned, 1953, 1955 (Box 6)
    -see also Ser. I, Richardson, Emily G.
  - Roberts, R. W. (Box 6)
  - Robinson, (Lt. Col.) Elliott S. (Box 6)
    -see Ser. I, Simmons, (Gen.) James S.
  - Rodkey, F. Lee, 1957-1958, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Rogers, Lore A., 1926, 1953, 1957 (Box 6)
    -see also Ser. I. ACS New York Section. William H. Nichols Medal
    -see also Ser. I, US Department of Agriculture
  - Rose, William C. (Box 6)